Institute of Public Policy Analysis fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Institute of Public Policy Analysis fonds
1972 - 1974
F-204
19 cm of textual records 2 architectural drawings
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
GENERAL NOTE Architectural drawings are found in file 4.
Financial assistance for the arrangement and description of these records and production of this finding aid was generously provided by Simon Fraser University's Office of the Vice-President, Academic (October 2005).
Institute of Public Policy Analysis
The Institute of Public Policy Analysis (IPPA) was a proposed institute that Simon Fraser University intended to establish as a forum bringing together individuals from the university, community and government sectors for the examination of Canadian public policy at both federal and provincial levels. The project was never realized.
Planning began in 1972 with the goal of commencing operations in September 1974. By early 1973 both Senate and the Board of Governors had approved the establishment of the Institute, and around March of that year the university appointed John Hogarth from the Faculty of Law at York University as the first Director. The Institute was to house both continuing staff funded by SFU as well as visiting fellows and researchers funded by external grants. Each academic year the Institute would focus on a specific problem or theme in public policy, offering symposia, research workshops, seminars and public lectures.
By early 1974 it had become apparent that the Institute would be unable to obtain sufficient external funding to begin its operations in the fall. Director Hogarth resigned effective March 31, 1974 and the university dissolved the Institute shortly afterwards.
published
Full
Published
The title of the fonds is based on the name of the creating body.
The fonds consists of records made or received by the Institute's Director in the course of planning the establishment of the Institute. Activities documented include development of the Institute's mandate, policies, and administrative structure; public programs planning; recruitment of staff, fellows, and conference participants; liaison with other SFU departments, faculty and staff associations, government, and other institutions; budget planning; facilities and space planning; and publicity and media relations. Document types include correspondence and reports; the proposal to establish the Institute, its charter and code of ethics, policies, and information brochure; conference proposals and invitations to potential participants; job applications, resumes, notes, and agreements; brochures, newsletters and other printed material from external associations and institutions offering comparable programs; costing estimates, budgets, funding strategy, correspondence and proposals to funding agencies; space planning reports and architectural drawings of the planned facilities for the Institute; and publicity material and press clippings relating to the Institute.
The material was arranged according to the original filing system of the creator. The Institute developed a file classification plan using the following categories:
AD: Administration
CO: Conferences
DO: Documentation
FO: Funding
MI: Miscellaneous
OR: Organisation
PE: Personnel
RE: Recruitment
UB: University bodies
Because of the small volume of files (30), the fonds was arranged without series. File titles include the original classification code and are listed alphabetically, grouping files by code.
Office of the Vice-President, Academic and Provost; Academic Planning Services; Hogarth, John; Architectural drawings; Textual records
The records formed part of a larger body of files under the control of Academic Planning Services which were appraised and transferred to the Archives in 1994 through a one-time Unscheduled Records Disposal (URD 083-94). This transfer was part of a larger project the Archives undertook to appraise, schedule and dispose of records that had accumulated in the University Records Centre through the 1980s and early 1990s.
All accessions have been processed as of February 2006. No further accruals are expected.
The files were originally accumulated by the Institute's Director, John Hogarth. Upon dissolution of the Institute in 1974, the material appears to have been transferred to the Office of the Vice-President, Academic. Subsequently the records were put in storage with a number of other closed series as a group of "Special Project Files" under the control of Academic Planning Services. In this form they were transferred to the Archives in 1994.
Other records relating to the Institute of Public Policy Analysis can be found in the fonds of the Office of the President (F-193); see series 12-1 (Faculty of Interdisciplinary Studies. Dean and general correspondence), file 4.
Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as required by law. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
A file list is available. The Institute's original file index is included in the fonds as file 1 (F-204-0-0-0-1).
- File index, 1973; F-204-0-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 204-1)
  published
  Textual records
  Pending review
- AD1 Budget, 1973; F-204-0-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 204-1)
  Creator's original file classification code: AD1.
- AD5 Administration - miscellaneous, 1973; F-204-0-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 204-1)
  Creator's original file classification code: AD5.
- AD6 Office, 1973; F-204-0-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 204-1)
  Creator's original file classification code: AD6.
- CO1 Conference structure, 1973; F-204-0-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 204-1)
  Creator's original file classification code: CO1.
- CO2 First year's conference, vol. 1, 1973; F-204-0-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 204-1)
  Creator's original file classification code: C02.
- CO2 First year's conference, vol. 2, 1973; F-204-0-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 204-1)
- DO1 Social indicators, 1972 - 1973; F-204-0-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 204-1)
  Creator's original file classification code: DO1.
- DO2 Ritchie Institute, 1972; F-204-0-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 204-1)
  Creator's original file classification code: DO2.
- DO3 Publications, 1973 - 1974; F-204-0-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 204-1)
  Creator's original file classification code: DO3.
- DO4 Clippings, 1973; F-204-0-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 204-1)
  Creator's original file classification code: DO4.
- FO1 Funding policy, 1973; F-204-0-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 204-1)
  Creator's original file classification code: FO1.
- FO2 Funding - general, 1973 - 1974; F-204-0-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 204-1)
  Creator's original file classification code: FO2.
- FO Funding - foundations and agencies, 1973 - 1974; F-204-0-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 204-1)
- M1 Miscellaneous, 1973; F-204-0-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 204-1)
  Creator's original file classification code: M1.
- M4 Canadian Labour Congress, 1973; F-204-0-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 204-1)
  Creator's original file classification code: M4.
- OR1 Charter and code of ethics, 1973 - 1974; F-204-0-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 204-1)
  Creator's original file classification code: OR1.
- OR2 Structure of Institute, 1973; F-204-0-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 204-1)
  Creator's original file classification code: OR2.
- OR3 Publication policy, 1973; F-204-0-0-0-19 (Archival box - small 204-2)
  Creator's original file classification code: OR3.
- OR4 Organization - miscellaneous, 1973; F-204-0-0-0-20 (Archival box - small 204-2)
  Creator's original file classification code: OR4.
- OR5 Budget, 1973; F-204-0-0-0-21 (Archival box - small 204-2)
  Creator's original file classification code: OR5.
- OR6 Structure of Institute (general), 1973 - 1974; F-204-0-0-0-22 (Archival box - small 204-2)
  Creator's original file classification code: OR6.
- PE5 Staff applications, 1973; F-204-0-0-0-23 (Archival box - small 204-2)
  Creator's original file classification code: PE5.
- PE6 Personnel - miscellaneous, 1973; F-204-0-0-0-24 (Archival box - small 204-2)
  Creator's original file classification code: PE6.
- RE1 Recruitment policy, 1973; F-204-0-0-0-25 (Archival box - small 204-2)
  Creator's original file classification code: RE1.
- RE2 Potential fellows, 1973; F-204-0-0-0-26 (Archival box - small 204-2)
  Creator's original file classification code: RE2.
- UB1 President's Office, 1973 - 1974; F-204-0-0-0-27 (Archival box - small 204-2)
  Creator's original file classification code: UB1.
- UB2 University business - general, 1973 - 1974; F-204-0-0-0-28 (Archival box - small 204-2)
  Creator's original file classification code: UB2.
- UB3 Faculty Association, 1973 - 1974; F-204-0-0-0-29 (Archival box - small 204-2)
  Creator's original file classification code: UB3.
- UB4 Staff Association, 1973; F-204-0-0-0-30 (Archival box - small 204-2)
  Creator's original file classification code: UB4.